ARMANDO SANCHEZ

Los Angeles, Ca. · 213-880-2436

armandosanchez855@yahoo.com · <u>www.linkedin.com/in/armando-sanchez-92b548229</u> · Portfolio: https://main.dsyf52c4veduj.amplifyapp.com/

Full Stack Web Developer with experience designing, developing, and testing web applications throughout the software development life cycle. As a self-learner, I can adapt to new things and always take on new challenges. Comprehensive knowledge in MySQL, MongoDB, React, Express, Node.js., Bootstrap, etc. skillful in creating servers and databases for functionality and designing and developing API's.

EXPERIENCE

2017 - PRESENT

MACHINE OPERATOR, ACCURATE STEEL HEAT TREATING/ION ACCURATE

Answer and respond to customer inquiries, requirements and needs. Provide excellent service to customers. Verify documents and reports in accordance with the merchandise in shop. Perform and execute functions relating to merchandise preparation, staging and outbound shipments. Monitor all inventory orders, using the documented data on orders to analyze supply and demand and make inventory projections. Create purchase orders. Operate tasks as a machine operator (furnaces) and ability to read blueprints.

2023 - PRESENT

FRONT-END DEVELOPER INTERN, THE STUDY SPOT

Build a frontend website used for tutoring services.

2015 - 2017

SALES ASSOCIATE/CUSTOMER SERVICE, UNDER ARMOUR INC.

Greeted customers, responded to questions, improved engagement with merchandise and provided outstanding customer service.

EDUCATION

JANUARY 2019

BACHELOR OF ARTS - SOCIOLOGY, CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERISTY OF LOS ANGELES

HARD SKILLS

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Fast Learner
- Detail Oriented

- Git & Github
- Visual Studio Code

- Bilingual Spanish & English
- Creative
- Persistent
- Driven
- Self-aware

- MongoDB Atlas
- Node Package Manager (NPM)
- Deploying a website
- Creating a website
- Navigating the terminal
- AJAX/ APIs

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATES

- Learn HTML Course (2021) Online Course- Codecademy
- Lean CSS Course (2021) Online Course- Codecademy
- Learn SQL Course (2022) Online Course- Codecademy
- Learn Node.js Course (2022) Online Course- Codecademy
- Learn Bootstrap Course (2022) Online Course- Codecademy
- Learn JavaScript Course (2022) Online Course Codecademy
- Learn React Course (2022) Online Course Codecademy
- Learn MongoDB Course (2022) Online Course Codecademy
- Connecting Front-End to Back-End Course (2022) Online Course Codecademy
- Deploy a website using AWS (2022) -Online Course Codecademy
- React-Router Certificate (2023) Online Course Codecademy

Projects

•